MATTHEW WIGHT

(+44)7804814652 • matthew.wight47@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/mattheww02

SUMMARY

Recently graduated Computer Science Master's student keen to be challenged and make an impact in the field of software development. Conscientious, hard-working and enthusiastic with an excellent academic record and several periods of experience working and volunteering in a wide variety of roles. Relevant experience with software development, project management, computer networks, machine learning and full stack development.

EDUCATION

Undergraduate Degree

2020 - 2024 University of Warwick

MEng Computer Science, 2:1 (68%)

Modules include: Software Engineering, Project Management, Database Systems, Algorithms, Operating Systems,

Neural Networks, Machine Learning, Data Analytics

A Level

2018 - 2020 Stretford Grammar School

Mathematics: A* Physics: A* Computer Science: A*

PROJECTS

Automated Image Geolocation OSINT (Master's Group Project)

2023 - 2024

- Worked as a team to design and implement an automated system to gather intelligence from images via deep learning and computer vision to achieve state-of-the-art performance on image geolocation tasks.
- Created a robust desktop app with intuitive interface and efficient back end to improve workflow for both intelligence experts and casual users.
- Utilised tech stack of Electron, Python/Django, SQLite, JavaScript/React and HTML as well as APIs from Google Cloud Platform and Azure.

Sentiment Analysis of Political News Articles (Undergraduate Dissertation)

2022 - 2023

- Utilised ML tools including Scikit-learn, TensorFlow and Keras to build an autoencoder-based deep learning model that would predict sentiment expressed in news articles, achieving an accuracy of 95%.
- Used data visualisation tools including Tableau and MatPlotLib to provide insight.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, C, C++, Java, C#, Bash, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Haskell, MATLAB

Software Engineering: agile, lean, test-driven development, CI/CD, OOP, project management, PRINCE2 & waterfall

DevOps & Cloud Services: Git, Docker, Azure, Jira, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform

EXPERIENCE

Department of Computer Science, University of Warwick: Graduate Teaching Assistant September 2023 - June 2024

- Taught students in use of Linux systems, Bash scripting, writing technical documents and Haskell programming
- Assisted with the delivery of labs sessions and providing feedback and guidance to students

Cove, Didsbury, Manchester: Bartender

Summer 2022

Took food and drinks orders from customers and prepared drinks in a restaurant with bar

Ark Nightclub, Deansgate, Manchester: Bartender

Summer 2021

Prepared drinks orders for customers and cleaned venue during and after opening hours

Pet's Corner, Chorlton, Manchester: Volunteer

October 2018 - November 2019

· Cared for various animals including goats, chickens, ducks, rabbits and hares

AWARDS

- UKMT Intermediate Mathematical Challenge Gold Award
- · UKMT Junior Mathematical Challenge Gold Award
- Stretford Grammar Sixth Form Certificates for Outstanding Achievement in Computer Science, Physics
- Stretford Grammar Sixth Form Certificates for Outstanding Effort in Computer Science, Mathematics

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

- Currently taking driving lessons (clean provisional license)
- Guitar playing (ten years playing electric and acoustic)
- Duke of Edinburgh Gold Award (pending, all sections completed)